<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>twoandahalfvan</title>
    <link href="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan" />
    <updated>2020-03-14T08:25:37+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Judith</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Fall in love with Valencia (in January)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Judith</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/how-we-fell-in-love-with-valencia-in-january/"/>
        <id>https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/how-we-fell-in-love-with-valencia-in-january/</id>
            <category term="Spain"/>

        <updated>2020-03-06T18:51:32+00:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/media/posts/11/Valencia-Map.JPG" alt="" />
                    On our way to escape winter in Germany we made it quickly through France, passed Barcelona and wanted to be as far away from upcoming snow as possible - winter was coming. However, Valencia happened to be on the way. And we stayed for a little&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/media/posts/11/Valencia-Map.JPG" alt="" />
                <p><strong>On our way to escape winter in Germany we made it quickly through France, passed Barcelona and wanted to be as far away from upcoming snow as possible - winter was coming. However, Valencia happened to be on the way. And we stayed for a little bit longer to fall in love with this city - even though storm Gloria hit us. </strong></p>
<p id="mcetoc_1e2hb67iq0">Valencia is Spain's third biggest city - after Madrid and Bareclona -, and it is the capital of the region as well as of the autonomous community also named Valencia (Spain and its <em>municipios</em>, <em>provincias</em> and <em>comunidades autonomas</em>...). It is located in the <em>Levante, la costa levantina, </em>which refers to Spain's east and the location on the Spanish Mediterranean coast.</p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e28o2ut80">Slow and spacious Valencia</h2>
<p>Even though around 800.000 people live in this beautiful city, it just does not feel crowded, let alone jammed with cars. In the city center or on shopping streets, we felt like we had enough air to breathe and space to stop for enjoyable rests. Nobody pushed us around while strolling slowly. It was not overcrowded with tourists although it definitely has the potential. Is this only due to off-season?</p>
<p>What is more: When you need a different scenery, you have perfect conditions. Stunning mountains and hikes in the backyard and a huge stretch of beach in its frontyard give you many possibilities to stretch your legs. </p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e28p6rsu1">Bike-friendly Valencia</h2>
<p>Talking about stretching your legs: Valencians ride two-wheelers, bikes or e-scooters. No wonder, because Valencia really is perfect to explore by bike. According to Wikipedia the city offers 108 km of bike lanes and EuroVelo, the network of cycling routes across Europe, passes through Valencia as well. Since we love riding bikes, we knew how we wanted to get through the city. Luckily, travelling in a camper also means you have everything you need with you. That is true for our bikes as well. </p>
<p>How was the biking experience? After you identify the bike lanes and get to know the street grid a little bit better, you manage just perfectly. Bigger streets offer seperate bike lanes in grass green. Smaller ones are directly labled as bike roads: cars where only allowed to drive 30km/h and are advised to pay attention to byciclists. Be aware: If there is a seperate bike lane, even when it is on the other side of the road (one bike lane often offers both directions), make sure to use it. Otherwise, cars might honk at you. </p>
<p>If you don't have your bike with you, no problem. There are plenty of bike rental shops in Valencia. Even better: Try Valenbisi (as in: Valencia bicicleta Sí!) with several stations across the city. Park and ride, ride and park - the better hop-on-hop-off service if you ask me. You can reach all the sights the city has to offer, and even the ones a little bit farer away. </p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e28q27en2">What sights to see in Valencia?</h2>
<ol>
<li>Definitely all the green there is, especially the park in the former Turia river, that went through Valencia: <strong>El Jardín del Turia</strong>. The "Turia garden" in the center stretches all the way from the Parque de Cabecera and Bioparc down to the Port of Valencia. Grab your bike and enjoy the ride under impressive bridges along orange trees and flowers. It is beautiful and sets the stage for outdoor activities like jogging, playing football/soccer or dancing. Even with all the bridges crossing the park it is hard to imagine that this park has been a river before. And it is even harder to imagine that after the big flood in 1957, government officials wanted to convert this area into more space for cars and roads. But luckily, <em>valencians </em>demanded to convert it into green space for the city. </li>
<li>When you ride or stroll along the Jardin del Turia in direction of the port, you won't miss it: la <i>Ciutat de les Arts i les Ciències, </i>the <strong>City of Arts and Sciences. </strong>(Is it just me or does it sound as if it where a place of GOT?) This cultural and architectural area is stunning, even if you won't go inside any of the buildings. I will just let these pictures speak for themselves: 
<div class="gallery"  > </div>
</li>
<li>Café and shops hopping in Russafa</li>
<li>Street art in El Carmen</li>
<li>Port Sa Platja</li>
<li>Beaches</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e28tu1vo0">Vegan in Valencia</h2>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Slideout Fridge</title>
        <author>
            <name>Judith</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/slideout-fridge/"/>
        <id>https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/slideout-fridge/</id>
            <category term="Shopping List"/>

        <updated>2020-02-27T22:48:14+00:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    We use a top loading fridge that uses a 12V compressor. The top loading helps on keeping the cold air inside the fridge when it is opened. The 12V compressor is currently the most energy efficient method for reliable cooling in all temperatures. The compressor&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>We use a top loading fridge that uses a 12V compressor. The top loading helps on keeping the cold air inside the fridge when it is opened. The 12V compressor is currently the most energy efficient method for reliable cooling in all temperatures. The compressor in the fridge that we have used is the exact same model as the one that is used in a more popular model that you see in a lot of van conversions. There are two key differences between these two models: Insulation and price. The model we use is slightly less well insulated and cheaper. If you are planning on installing solar in your van, then there is always enough power for a 12V fridge when it is hot, so the weaker insulation actually becomes an advantage: Less wasted space and weight.</p>
<p>DACH: <a rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" href="https://amzn.to/2HY3orA">https://amzn.to/2HY3orA</a></p>
<p>USA: <a rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" href="https://amzn.to/2w81faj">https://amzn.to/2w81faj</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Drawer and Fridge Slides</title>
        <author>
            <name>Judith</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/drawer-and-fridge-slides/"/>
        <id>https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/drawer-and-fridge-slides/</id>
            <category term="Shopping List"/>

        <updated>2020-02-27T22:48:21+00:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    For the drawers and the fridge we use full extension slides that are soft closing and self closing. We think these slides are ideal for mobile homes since the self retracting mechanism (a simple spring) helps in keeping the drawers in place while driving. You&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>For the drawers and the fridge we use full extension slides that are soft closing and self closing. We think these slides are ideal for mobile homes since the self retracting mechanism (a simple spring) helps in keeping the drawers in place while driving. You will still need a proper locking mechanism for the drawers that have dangerous or heavy contents. On the other hand, the soft closing mechanism makes these slides a joy to use, as you don't need to worry about how hard you slam those drawers.</p>
<p>Make sure to order the right length!</p>
<p>DACH: <a rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" href="https://amzn.to/2T2GPIG">https://amzn.to/2T2GPIG</a></p>
<p>USA: <a rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" href="https://amzn.to/2Tk8uUp">https://amzn.to/2Tk8uUp</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Individual sized shower tub</title>
        <author>
            <name>Judith</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/individual-sized-shower-tub/"/>
        <id>https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/individual-sized-shower-tub/</id>
            <category term="Shopping List"/>

        <updated>2020-03-06T17:54:58+00:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/media/posts/7/teaser-shower-tub.jpg" alt="van shower" />
                    This 1.5mm thick stainless steel shower tub is built according to your dimensions, which mean it will take a while. You can specify the number and position of the drainage points. You will need additional 1.5mm thick stainless steel sheets for the walls of the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/media/posts/7/teaser-shower-tub.jpg" alt="van shower" />
                <p>This 1.5mm thick stainless steel shower tub is built according to your dimensions, which mean it will take a while. You can specify the number and position of the drainage points.</p>
<p>You will need additional 1.5mm thick stainless steel sheets for the walls of the shower. You can source these sheets from your local metal shop.</p>
<p>If you need more info on how to build this type of shower, take a look at our article on [how to build a space saving shower]</p>
<p>DACH: <a rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" href="https://shop.versandmetall.de/de/wohnmobil-zubehoer/edelstahl-duschwannen-duschtassen-fuer-wohnmobile/">https://shop.versandmetall.de/de/wohnmobil-zubehoer/edelstahl-duschwannen-duschtassen-fuer-wohnmobile/</a></p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Garage Slideout</title>
        <author>
            <name>Judith</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/standardized-boxes/"/>
        <id>https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/standardized-boxes/</id>
            <category term="Shopping List"/>

        <updated>2020-02-27T22:49:50+00:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/media/posts/6/eurobox-flap-side.jpg" alt="" />
                    For the garage slideout, we use heavy duty full extension slides. These slides are meant for heavy loads and unlike the [drawer and fridge slides] they do not have a self retracting or soft closing mechanism but a locking function, that keeps them in place&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/media/posts/6/eurobox-flap-side.jpg" alt="" />
                <p><span style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, Arial, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Fira Sans', 'Droid Sans', 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif, 'Apple Color Emoji', 'Segoe UI Emoji', 'Segoe UI Symbol'; font-size: inherit;">For the garage slideout, we use heavy duty full extension slides. These slides are meant for heavy loads and unlike the [drawer and fridge slides] they do not have a self retracting or soft closing mechanism but a locking function, that keeps them in place while driving.</span></p>
<p>DACH: <a rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" href="https://amzn.to/388QYI2">https://amzn.to/388QYI2</a></p>
<p>USA: <a rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" href="https://amzn.to/32vXYgQ">https://amzn.to/32vXYgQ</a></p>
<p>We use standard size boxes (called Euro Boxes) with a side door for easy access when the boxes are stacked. This is both practical and weight saving, as you only need one set of heavy duty slides. We are very happy with this choice, as it keeps the garage organised with a minimal amount of effort.</p>
<p>DACH: <a rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" href="https://www.obi.de/aufbewahrungsboxen/obi-eurobox-system-tauro-box-flap-side-40-x-30-x-22-cm-transparent/p/2615755">https://www.obi.de/aufbewahrungsboxen/obi-eurobox-system-tauro-box-flap-side-40-x-30-x-22-cm-transparent/p/2615755</a></p>
<p>USA: Unfortunately the Euro Box system is not established in the USA. There seems to be a high demand for these boxes, so if you are interested in trading them in bulk and have experience in importing larger quantities, let us know and we will get you the contact details from the manufacturer.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Water Tank: Space saving options?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Judith</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/water-tank/"/>
        <id>https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/water-tank/</id>
            <category term="Shopping List"/>

        <updated>2020-03-06T17:55:04+00:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/media/posts/5/watertank-teaser.jpg" alt="van watertank " />
                    This space saving 90 litre water tank fits above the right wheel well of any Fiat Ducato, Citroen Jumper, Peugeot Boxer or Ram Promaster built after 2006. Not sure if it fits other vans too. It comes with several prefabricated holes and connections: Two maintenance&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/media/posts/5/watertank-teaser.jpg" alt="van watertank " />
                <p><img class="post__image post__image--left" src="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/media/posts/5/van-watertank-90l.jpg" alt="watertank" width="672" height="320">This space saving 90 litre water tank fits above the right wheel well of any Fiat Ducato, Citroen Jumper, Peugeot Boxer or Ram Promaster built after 2006. Not sure if it fits other vans too. It comes with several prefabricated holes and connections: Two maintenance lids on the top, one inlet and one outlet. The outlet is 26mm pipe that is molded on the bottom of the tank, so you must drill a hole in your van and attach a ball valve on the outside.  </p>
<p>Unfortunately, it seems to be only available in Europe.</p>
<p>EU: <a href="https://www.campingwagner.de/product_info.php/info/p62200_Frischwassertank-fuer-Vans--90l.html">https://www.campingwagner.de/product_info.php/info/p62200_Frischwassertank-fuer-Vans--90l.html</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Planning your layout</title>
        <author>
            <name>Judith</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/planning-your-layout/"/>
        <id>https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/planning-your-layout/</id>
            <category term="Van Build"/>
            <category term="Planning"/>

        <updated>2020-02-29T20:32:30+00:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/media/posts/4/pascal-debrunner-1059218-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                    Planning is an important step when converting a van to a livable home. Many people skimp on this. If you skimp in the beginning, you're probably gonna skimp later on in the build too. So, don't skip the planning phase. You don't need to create&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/media/posts/4/pascal-debrunner-1059218-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                <p><strong>Planning is an important step when converting a van to a livable home. Many people skimp on this. If you skimp in the beginning, you're probably gonna skimp later on in the build too. So, don't skip the planning phase.</strong></p>
<p>You don't need to create a 3D model in order to plan your build. You can start simple, get a piece of paper and a pen and start drawing. If you are unsure about your layout, add in some scissors and create individual items representing your bed, your toilet, your shower etc. Then rearrange until you like it.</p>
<p>Or if you have the space, get some tape and create your van layout in its actual size on the floor. This way you get a good feeling about the size and where you might need to add a couple of centimeters.</p>
<p>That being said, modelling your van in 3D is a very helpful step. It will help you solve problems before they even exist. Which means that it will help you save money, because you don't have to build things multiple times before they work the way you want to. </p>
<p>To get things started, I recommend downloading Sketchup Make, then watch Greg Virgoe's wunderful tutorial on how to draw your van and repeat his steps.</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/b47sF7l1yDM" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>By the way, if you haven't done already, check out Greg Virgoe's build videos. Absolutely brilliant!</p>
<p>Anyway, after you have figured out the basics of Sketchup you will find that you can rearrange things pretty quickly and get a good spatial feeling about the different van layouts. </p>
<p>We have tried various layouts and at the end, we decided on this one. You might need to click the model and wait a little before you can interact with it. Enjoy.</p>
<p> </p>
<iframe width="580" height="326" src="https://3dwarehouse.sketchup.com/embed/a645e56d-ffdb-4e38-8299-3afbe6f0b9c9" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Van Tour without frills!</title>
        <author>
            <name>Judith</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/van-tour/"/>
        <id>https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/van-tour/</id>
            <category term="Vanlife"/>

        <updated>2020-03-06T18:14:23+00:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/media/posts/3/vantour-teaser-image.jpg" alt="vantour twoandahalfvan" />
                    How to describe our camper build? I guess not a thousand words could describe what a short video tour does. So here you have it: a video van tour of our converted Citroen Jumper. With a high roof, long body and extended wheelbase (L4H3) there is plenty&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/media/posts/3/vantour-teaser-image.jpg" alt="vantour twoandahalfvan" />
                <p><strong>How to describe our camper build? I guess not a thousand words could describe what a short video tour does. So here you have it: a video van tour of our converted Citroen Jumper. With a high roof, long body and extended wheelbase (L4H3) there is plenty to see.</strong> </p>
<p>Our van tour on our <a href="youtube.com/twoandahlafvan">YouTube channel twoandahalfvan</a>:</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Uh5xXAoELaY" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" ></iframe></p>
<p>This build took us about ten months of hard work, tears and a lot of laughter. What is not in the video: the intense planning that went ahead. Please check out our <a href="../../../../../planning">planning process and 3D model</a>. This helped us a lot to visualize and to grasp the whole project. </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Packing list: What do we need in the van?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Judith</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/packing-list-what-do-we-need-in-the-van/"/>
        <id>https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/packing-list-what-do-we-need-in-the-van/</id>
            <category term="Vanlife"/>

        <updated>2020-03-11T18:07:23+00:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/media/posts/16/Van_coffee.JPG" alt="" />
                    Storage on 8 squaremeters can be a tricky thing. Especially, when you have too much of everything in your household. You had to be prepared for big dinner parties, right? And it gets even trickier, if you are emotionally attached to things (like I am). But let's&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/media/posts/16/Van_coffee.JPG" alt="" />
                <p><strong>Storage on 8 squaremeters can be a tricky thing. Especially, when you have too much of everything in your household. You had to be prepared for big dinner parties, right? And it gets even trickier, if you are emotionally attached to things (like I am). But let's face it: What has to be in the van? </strong></p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e297ro270">Kitchen area</h2>
<p>Well, you probably won't host Christmas dinner parties for your family. Even if you like to invite friends and fellow campers, they often can bring their own cuttlery since they travel in a camper as well. For our two person van-household we pretty much only need: </p>
<ul>
<li>2 plates </li>
<li>2 big bowls (great for Müsli, salads, soups, dessert, ..)</li>
<li>2 emaille cups (that also serve as wine cups)</li>
<li>2 bread knives</li>
<li>2 forkes </li>
<li>4 small spoons (extra spoons for dips etc)</li>
<li>2 big spoons </li>
<li>...</li>
</ul>
<p>You get the picture. After usage, we wash our dishes directly. There is a) no dish washing machine to store dirty cuttlery and b) no space to leave it lying around all day, especially when we move on to another campsite. This means, we really only need what we have to use for one meal. After washing it, it is ready for the next round. So ask yourself: Why would you need 4 forkes? Or 4 plates? We also made sure to have the one perfect pan for every dish. One big pan with a high border plus a medium sized pot for pasta and rice is all we need. </p>
<p>The other storage space in the kitchen is taken by plastic or glass storage boxes, italian espresso maker, milk foaming machine (ok this you don't really need, but we did not want to miss a foamy latte), and lots and lots of food. </p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e2vv4uj20">Clothes and gear</h2>
<p>Honestly: We packed way too much clothing. I have read before that you should take as much clothing as you would need for a 3 weeks vacation. However, standing infront of your closet you cannot do it. I could not do it. So I stuffed every corner of my new tiny closet in the van with clothes. I really thought, or maybe only wanted to believe, that I would need all the shirts and shorts and sport gear. Let me tell you: You do not. I should have listen to the blog posts that told me to only pack for a 3 week vacation. Of course, you might need a little bit more since you travel through seasons. Even though we try to avoid winter, we still have to face chilly nights and cold days. Some comfy sweaters are a must.  </p>
<p>But really: You wear your favorite clothes and then you wash them and you wear them again. There are so many pieces I haven't touched. </p>
<p> </p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e297ro272">Activities and leisure</h2>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e297ro273">Toiletry</h2>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e297ro274">Space - for what's to come</h2>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How to prepare for vanlife</title>
        <author>
            <name>Judith</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/how-to-prepare-for-vanlife/"/>
        <id>https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/how-to-prepare-for-vanlife/</id>
            <category term="Vanlife"/>

        <updated>2020-03-10T20:44:43+00:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/media/posts/12/Prepare-Vanlife.JPG" alt="" />
                    From "What do you think of vanlife?" and "Would be nice to travel in a van!" to actually doing it, you come a long way. But how do you prepare for such a life changing event? Actually, you cannot - a least not to 100&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://debueb.github.io/twoandahalfvan/media/posts/12/Prepare-Vanlife.JPG" alt="" />
                <p><strong>From "What do you think of vanlife?" and "Would be nice to travel in a van!" to actually doing it, you come a long way. But how do you prepare for such a life changing event? Actually, you cannot - a least not to 100 %. </strong></p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e297btic2">Hello internet! </h2>
<p>First of all, you want to start searching YouTube, Instagram or Pinterest and also discussion boards online for vanlife stories. So many people are living in a van and luckily they document it online, all the pros and cons. You can learn a lot from other people's experiences, skills, successes and mistakes. Could this life be for you? </p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1e32sfgrg0">Some examples of helpful content</h3>
<ul>
<li></li>
<li><a href="https://forum.camper-bauen.de/">https://forum.camper-bauen.de/</a> (awesome content, discussions, helpful vanlifers - only in German)</li>
</ul>
<p>Do not only scavenge YouTube etc. for experiences though. Use it for inspiration and education as well. What solutions do you like? How did other vanlifers manage the questions you will come across: from electricity to carpentry. Start saving videos and ideas, pin them to boards or write them down. You will come back to them later while planning and building your van. For us, making up our mind about ideas and planning the van took even longer than actually building it. And we often asked ourselves: "Where have we seen the solution? What video was it again?"</p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e2974ecl0">Minimalistic thinking </h2>
<p>What do you really need in your life to be happy or thankful? Start thinking about your habits and definitely the materialistic objects that suround you. What makes you appreciate your time and makes you smile? What objects haven't you touched in years? Because here is the undeniable truth: Not every thing and not every hobby can go with you! This is a good thing though. We consume and buy far too much new stuff anyway. Vanlife is the big chance for you to realize: You really don't need much to feel good. Think about it: When moving to another place have you ever noticed how much stuff relocates untouched from box to another box? Or how much things are thrown away?</p>
<p>Well, moving into a van is just like that, the biggest relocation of your life probably. Except for the fact, that you won't have that much storage anymore. But don't throw everything away. Sell or give it away. And if you cannot let go of certain things, if you are emotionally attached, you can still find storage for them, maybe with friends or relatives.  </p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e32s5thg0">Sustainable thinking </h2>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e297ftfk3">..but what about private space? </h2>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e297g1754">.. and the toilet situation? </h2>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
